(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
スイートマジック
作詞・作曲：Junky
Sweet Magic
Lyrics/Composition: Junky
甘くて幸せなこと
Something sweet and happy
隠し味何にしよう
What should the secret ingredient be?
純粋な乙女心
A pure maiden's heart
甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
Must involve a sweet love too
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Layering sadness, mille-feuille
酸味も積み上げタルト
A tart piled with acidity
苦味はチョコレートケーキ？
Is bitterness for a chocolate cake?
魔法かけた甘い奇跡
A sweet miracle cast with magic
甘さを抑えてビターとか
Like reducing sweetness for bitter...
ミルクなしのコーヒーとか
Or coffee without milk...
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの？
Can't I become an adult with just sweetness?
そんなの絶対、絶対やだやだやだ
I absolutely, absolutely hate that!
「召し上がれ　お嬢様？」
"Enjoy your meal, My Lady?"
甘い罠　ほら　虜にしてあげる
A sweet trap, look, I'll make you a captive
そんな魔法かけるから
Because I'll cast such magic
ちょっとだけ待たせてあげるわ
I'll make you wait just a little bit
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite wasn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたく意地張って
Stubborn like a red strawberry,
甘いとこなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side,
完璧に作るもん
Because I'll make it perfectly,
一人でも、でも、でも
Even if I'm all alone, but, but...
ねえ 気付いてんでしょ？
Hey, you've noticed, haven't you?
わかってんでしょ？
You understand, don't you?
隠し味の恋心
The secret ingredient is my love,
苦みとか 酸味とか
Bitterness, acidity,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Those things are fine once in a while,
意地っ張りで わがままな
Stubborn and selfish,
そんな甘い魔法使い
I'm that kind of sweet magic user.
Yeah...
Ah...
マジカル
Magical
迷子迷子 真っ只中 さあ
Lost, lost, right in the middle, come on!
パノラマ パラノイア
Panorama, paranoia,
ギコギコ 迷い心 剪定
Creak-creak, pruning the wavering heart,
パノラマ パラノイア
Panorama, paranoia,
退路退路 断った絡まった
Escape route, escape route, cut off and entangled,
パノラマ パラノイア
Panorama, paranoia,
サッドサッド 伏して パラ
Sad, sad, face down, para-
パラノイド
Paranoid.
バババグ さバグバグ
Ba-ba-bug, sa-bug-bug,
タタタグ 才能のタグ
Ta-ta-tag, tag of talent,
ハハハグ 感情はハグ
Ha-ha-hug, emotion is a hug,
発症 苦しいは嫌嫌嫌
Onset, being in pain is no, no, no,
嫌嫌 絶叫な感情落下
No, no, a screaming emotional drop,
パッパラノイア 溺れ声上げてはぐるぐる
Pa-pa-paranoia, drowning voice rising round and round,
まあ！絶体絶命なやたらめったら
Oh! A desperate situation, blindly,
沈め夢夢 嫌嫌嫌
Sinking, dreams, dreams, no, no, no,
バババグ
Ba-ba-bug,
的外れズレ 嫌嫌
Off target, out of alignment, no, no,
バババグ
Ba-ba-bug,
答え絶え絶え 嫌嫌嫌
Answer gasping, no, no, no,
嫌嫌嫌
No, no, no.
ぐるぐる ぱっかん 待って ほら待って
Round and round, popping, wait, hold on, wait,
無理ぐるぐる せーので回れ
Impossible, round and round, on three, spin!
あっぱっかん ほらやっぱ無理ぐるぐる
Ah, popping, as I thought, impossible, round and round,
暗夜に鎖
Chains in the dark night,
エンドレス病み？ あはん
Endless sickness? Ah-han,
だっこだっこ いらない子だ
Hold me, hold me, I'm an unwanted child,
パノラマ パラノイア
Panorama, paranoia,
いい子いい子 「頑張れ」の範濫
Good child, good child, an overflow of 'good luck,'
アドミニストレイター
Administrator.
バババグ さバグバグ
Ba-ba-bug, sa-bug-bug,
ラララグラフ タイムラグ
La-la-la-graph, time lag,
ロロログ 反抗のログ
Lo-lo-log, log of rebellion,
パパパグ パパパラノイア
Pa-pa-bug, pa-pa-paranoia,
パパパラノイア 嫌嫌嫌
Pa-pa-paranoia, no, no, no,
さあ 絶叫な感情落下
Come on, a screaming emotional drop,
パッパラノイア 左右行方もぐるぐる
Pa-pa-paranoia, left and right, direction is round and round,
悲惨！限界の狂想でやたらめったら
Disastrous! Blindly in a limit rhapsody,
病み迷え 嫌嫌嫌
Wandering in sickness, no, no, no,
嫌嫌絶叫な感情落下
No, no, a screaming emotional drop,
パッパラノイア 溺れ声上げてはぐるぐる
Pa-pa-paranoia, drowning voice rising round and round,
まあ！絶体絶命なやたらめったら
Oh! A desperate situation, blindly,
枯れ果て 嫌嫌嫌
Withered away, no, no, no,
バババグ
Ba-ba-bug,
パパパレアレ 嫌嫌
Pa-pa-pale-ale, no, no,
バババグ
Ba-ba-bug,
ドロまみれ 嫌嫌嫌
Covered in mud, no, no, no,
嫌嫌嫌
No, no, no,
No, no, no.
はいっ！よいしょ！
Alright! Heave-ho!
というわけで、皆殿！こんバデござるー！
So then, everyone! Good evening-de gozaru!
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの用心棒、
Hololive 6th gen, bodyguard of Secret Society holoX,
侍の風真いろはでござる！わーいわーいわーい！
Samurai Kazama Iroha-de gozaru! Yay, yay, yay!
というわけで、本日は誕生日の生誕ライブへ
And so, thank you so much for coming to
お越しいただきありがとうございます！
my birthday celebration live stream today!
今日のことはですね、ここっ！これっ！
About today's event, right here! This!
「風真いろは生誕ライブ2023」で
Using '#風真いろは生誕ライブ2023',
たくさんね、スクショとか感想とか、いっぱいいっぱい呟いてくださいね！
Please tweet lots and lots of screenshots and impressions!
はい、というわけで早速ね、2曲続けて歌って躍らせていただきました。
Okay, so I've just performed two songs in a row.
スイートマジックとバクでしたー！
They were 'Sweet Magic' and 'Baku'!
歌も踊りもめちゃくちゃ頑張りました。
I worked really hard on both the singing and dancing.
頑張ったよ、みんな。絞り出しちゃった、最初から。
I did my best, everyone. I gave it my all right from the start.
はい、ちょっとね、昨日のカウントダウンではケーキを食べ損ねたござんなんですけど、
Well, I missed out on eating cake during yesterday's countdown,
まずはステージのね、紹介をしていきたいと思います。後ろにケーキが見えてるもんね。
but first, I'd like to introduce the stage. You can see the cake behind me, right?
というわけで、ステージ、皆殿、見てください！
So, everyone, please take a look at the stage!
今回、誕生日ライブ用に設えていただきました！わーい！
It was specially set up for this birthday live! Yay!
でっかいケーキ！食べたい。昨日食べ損ねたんですけど。
A huge cake! I want to eat it. I missed out yesterday, though.
皆殿は今、ケーキ食べたり、なんかおいしいもんとかね、飲んだり食べたりしながらライブを見てくださっているんでしょうか？
Is everyone watching the live while eating cake or something delicious?
このね、1時間は全力で風真も皆殿のこと、楽しませますので、
I'll be giving it my all for this hour to make sure you all have a great time,
最後まで楽しみにしていてくださいね！
so please look forward to it until the very end!
はあ、激しくてまだ滑舌が回ってないんですけど。
It was so intense that my tongue is still a bit tied.
そして今回はですね、誕生日ということで、なんと今日のためにゲストの方からメッセージをいただいているというちょっとことで、
And since it's my birthday, I've actually received a message from a guest for today,
今日一それがソワソワしているんですけど。
which I've been feeling a bit restless about all day.
まだ風真も見てないんですよ、そのメッセージ。
I haven't even seen the message yet myself.
なのでちょっと、どんな内容かウキウキソワソワゴザゴザルなんですけど。え、そろそろ来るのかな？大丈夫かな？楽しみ。
So I'm really excited and nervous to see what's in it. Is it coming soon? Is it okay? I'm looking forward to it.
あ、あ、来た来た来た！あ、来た。おお、来ましたね。
Oh, oh, it's here, it's here! Ah, it's here. Oh, there it is.
早速1つ目のメッセージが届いたようでござる。
It seems the first message has arrived!
風真殿。風真殿。
Kazama-dono. Kazama-dono.
聞こえますか？日々聞いて感じて考えてますか？
Can you hear me? Are you hearing, feeling, and thinking every day?
白上は今、月にいます。
Shirakami is on the moon right now.
やばい、なみだ。
Oh no, I'm crying.
なんか遠くに赤いモヤモヤとか白っぽいのとか、なんか近くにウサギがいっぱいいるんですけど。
There's some red and white mist in the distance, and lots of rabbits nearby.
そんな亜空間に来ております。
I've come to such a strange space.
風真殿、お誕生日おめでとう。
Kazama-dono, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます、おめで、イエーイ！
Thank you very much, happy... yay!
足元にあった石っころを蹴ってしまいました。
I just kicked a pebble that was at my feet.
いや、風真殿とはね、やっぱりこれに関係するゲームのお話でいっぱい盛り上がったりとかできたので、本当にそれが一番嬉しかったですね、白上は。
Well, with Kazama-dono, we've been able to get really excited talking about games related to this, so Shirakami was really happy about that.
やはり共通の趣味を持っている仲間というのは、良き。
After all, having friends with common hobbies is a good thing.
わかる。
I get it.
またゲーム内でもいいですし、ちょっとあの、一緒にコンサートにも行った仲なので。
It could be in-game again, or... since we're friends who went to a concert together.
楽しかったです。
It was fun.
またカフェとかも一緒にね、一回行ったけど、またぜひ行きましょう。
We also went to a cafe together once, so let's definitely go again.
めっちゃ嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
ということでね、ちょっとそっちの方に今から白上、えんせんとテレポするから受け止めてくれ。
So, Shirakami is going to teleport over there now, so please catch me!
えんせんとテレポ。待ってる。
Teleporting... I'm waiting.
ドーン！
Boom!
飛んでった。どこから来るんだ？
She flew off. Where is she coming from?
しんでしまうとはなさけない！
It's a shame to die!
お！ しんでしまうとは なさけない！
Oh! It's a shame to die!
３ ２ １ アウ！
3 2 1 Ow!
「おー！ なに？ へーの！ なに？ おとじゃ！ うーむ！」
King! What? Soldier! What? Younger brother! Yes.
「ひめが さらわれました！」
The princess has been kidnapped.
「勇者は？」 「いません」 「うーむ… そうだ！」
Where's the hero? Not here. Hmm... I know!
「かくたてうえば おまえが ゆうしゃだ！ って、ぼったい」
Then you're the hero! Wait, that's not right.
さあ さあ たからばこのなかみと この なけなしのかねで たびだって
Now then, take what's in the treasure chest and this pittance of money and set off,
なかまを さがして モンスター たおして てきとうじゃねえか
find some friends, and defeat some monsters. Sounds about right, doesn't it?
とにかく こまったら まちの ひとびとに はなしかけようぜ
Anyway, if you're stuck, just talk to the townspeople.
ボスが ぜんぜん たおせる たおせる マジで？！
You can totally defeat the boss! Really?!
いばって いばって いばって たおせ とつげきさいに いちばんのりから
Swagger and swagger and swagger, and defeat him! Be the first to charge in!
にどねを してやるぜ まったくもって うえから めせんすぎるぜ
Then I'll go back to sleep. You're being way too condescending.
けいけんち けいけんち けいけんち つんで もっと きょうだんな なかまと たのしいたびを
Get experience, experience, experience, and have a fun journey with stronger friends!
ていうか わたしは いっせーぼくぜ つぎつぎ かかげて デリベリーデリベリー
I mean, I'm just here for the ride. Let's deliver one thing after another!
そなたが ラスボスを たおしてくるひを たのしみに まっておるぞい
I'll be looking forward to the day you defeat the last boss!
せかいへいわを とりもどすため おくにの へいわを まもるため
To restore world peace, to protect the peace of our country,
いちばんうしろで しきを とります そなたの けいけんち ぼくたちに ください
I'll lead from the very back. Give us your experience points!
あなたの ために せかいの ために たたかう ぼくらの あいこくしん
For you, for the world, our patriotism fights on.
なかまも しんで ぜつめつすんぜん やっぱり レベルが たりねえ
Our friends are dead, and we're on the verge of extinction. After all, our level isn't high enough.
あなたの パーティーは ぜんめつしました。 おおかみさま。
Your party has been wiped out. Lord Wolf.
おお、死んでしまうとはなさけない！
Oh, it's pathetic that you died!
王様、なんです？
King, what's wrong?
もう、もー無理です！
Jeez, it's already impossible!
ええい、弱音を吐くとはもっと情けない！
Hmph, showing weakness is even more pathetic!
経験値、経験値、共に申し分ない。
Experience points, experience points, both are impeccable.
優秀な人材も潤沢、人望厚いね。
Talented people are also abundant, you have a lot of support.
かといって慢性的、な問題は、国家レベルのコンポーザー。
However, a chronic problem is the composer at a national level.
よく言えば猛、悪く言えばおバカ。
To put it nicely, fierce; to put it badly, stupid.
正真正銘、全人類は戦闘民族。
Genuine, all humanity is a warrior race.
言わずもがな。
Needless to say.
協調性や順応性が重要なんて、
Cooperation and adaptability are important?
浮世は空疎だ。
The world is hollow.
次のレベルになるには、あと世ポイントの経験が。
To reach the next level, more experience in afterlife points.
さらにはもっと自己主張が必要なら挫けるな。
If more self-assertion is needed, don't give up.
パリィサポロッポ、ザンシパロント。
Parry-saporoppo, zanshi-paront.
魔法使いも使い物になってきたな。
The wizard has become useful too.
勇者、サクサク、面笑いで、
Hero, quickly, with a smile on your face,
御託ばっか並べて、癪に障るぜ。
Just listing off excuses, it's annoying.
ハリィハリィハリィ、ばっか、
Harry, harry, harry, fool,
そりゃおハリバッカでバッカ。
That's just a bunch of debugging fools.
なまものの私を眠らすなんて、
Making me, a living thing, sleep,
あんた一体何者、さては無風か？
Who on earth are you? Are you an outlaw?
僕は勇者じゃありません、
I'm not the hero,
むしろ、王が勇者だと思いまーす！
Rather, I think the King is the hero!
世界平和を取り戻すため。
To restore world peace.
お国の平和を守るため。
To protect the peace of the country.
最前線に身を投じませ。
Throw yourself onto the front lines.
支持率アップは目に見えた。
The rise in approval ratings was visible.
さぁほら。
Come on, look.
権益のため、お金のために。
For the sake of interests, for the sake of money.
戦う王様、何を見る？
The fighting King, what do you see?
この絵、禁止で、絶滅寸前。
This picture is forbidden, on the verge of extinction.
死んでしまうとは、情けない！
It's pathetic that you died!
世界平和を取り戻すため。
To restore world peace.
あなたの笑顔を守るため。
To protect your smile.
魔王軍、大炎上。
The Demon King's army is in big flames.
芋煮、ガラガラ、かき集め。
Imoni, rattling, gathering up.
今日も今日とて、死んじゃっている。
Today again, they are dying.
真の勇者を待っている。
Waiting for the true hero.
他力本願ではありません。
It's not about relying on others.
こちらの奴らには、敵わねー！
We can't beat these guys!
いろはちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Iroha-chan, happy birthday!
おー、いつものおかゆ先輩の背景だ、なんか安心する。
Oh, it's Okayu-senpai's usual background, it's somewhat comforting.
お祝いできて、すっごく嬉しいよ。
I'm so happy to be able to celebrate with you.
あ、やった、嬉しい。
Ah, yay, I'm happy.
いろはちゃんとは、ミクスを通して、すっごく仲良くなったよね。
Iroha-chan and I became very close through MiKus, right?
え、そうなんです。
Eh, that's right.
あの時は、本当に手取り足取り教えてくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much for teaching me everything step by step back then.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
また一緒に、クレープとか、オムライスとか、
I'd like to go eat crepes or omurice together again,
食べに行きたいなーなんて。
or something like that.
行きたい、行きましょう。
I want to go, let's go.
それに、いろはちゃんは、いつも会う時に、
And Iroha-chan always gives me
美味しい手作りお菓子をくれるんだよね。
delicious homemade sweets when we meet.
最高の女。
The best woman.
それが風真いろは、なんだよなぁ。
That's Kazama Iroha for you.
また食べに来てください。
Please come eat again.
いつまでも、いろはちゃんは、僕の可愛ゆい後輩だよ。
Iroha-chan will always be my cute junior.
やったー。
Yay-.
本当に大好き。
I really love you.
これからも、いっぱい遊ぼうね。
Let's play a lot from now on, too.
やったー、ぜひこれからもよろしくお願いします。
Yay, please look forward to working with me from now on too.
もうこんな時間だ。
It's already this time.
ネコネコワープで、そちらへ向かいます！
I'm headed there via Neko-Neko Warp!
ネコネコワープ？
Neko-Neko Warp?
痛いことは、嫌いですが、
I hate painful things,
君の手のひらは嫌いじゃない。
but I don't hate your palm.
言葉は飴、玉みたいに、
Words are like candy,
甘く広がって心満たす。
spreading sweetly and filling the heart.
あー、全然分かってない、永遠に言う通り。
Ah, I don't understand at all, just like you say forever.
風に触れ、じゃない。
Not like touching the wind.
あー、何で聞いてない、もっともっとあの子みたいに。
Ah, why aren't you listening, more and more like that girl.
可愛くならなくちゃ。
I have to become cute.
愛情は透明に。
Affection becomes transparent.
証拠は派手めに。
The evidence should be flashy.
もう、だいたい、大概のことは分からなくなる。
Geez, mostly, I start not understanding most things.
閻魔叩き、朱にご褒美。
Enma-tataki, reward in vermilion.
もう、嫌って離されないように。
Geez, so that I won't be hated and let go.
今日だってちゃんと内緒の手袋、
Even today, I'll be a good girl
にゃんて良い子にするから、愛して。
with my secret gloves, so love me.
Everybody, today is lovely day.
Candy candy, is my candy.
Any any anytime it fits me.
Gimmie gimmie, love me my darling.
合いたい、お間違い、なんてみんなは言う。
Want to meet, you're wrong, everyone says.
取り憑かれているって。
That I'm obsessed.
ならこの胸で疼く締め付けるような切なさは何なの。
Then what is this tightening sorrow aching in this chest?
選ぶ言葉。
The words I choose.
戸惑い。
Bewilderment.
指差し
Pointing fingers,
隠せないよ　好顔
can't hide my happy face.
しがみ付いた
I clung to you,
貴方の
even your...
あーあ　機嫌も　じかして　脳内
Ah... mood, teasing my brain.
優しく撫でてくれるのかな
I wonder if you'll stroke me gently.
君のそれが　耐えられるの？
Can I endure that side of yours?
紹介で　私だけなんだよね
It's just me in your intro, right?
あからさまに　身体まさに
So obviously, my body truly...
もう嫌だって　離れられないよね
Even if I say I hate it, I can't leave.
そうだよ、め！
That's right, bad!
感情は徐々に　歌えば少々に
Emotions gradually, singing just a little,
もう酸いも甘いも　転がせばいい
both the sour and the sweet, just let them roll.
柑橘の匂い　立って　身を退くのだ
The scent of citrus rises, so back off.
もう　困って　叱られるだけだし
I'm already in trouble, and I'll just get scolded.
今日だってちゃんと膝でおとなしく
Even today, I'll be good on your lap.
にゃー手を好きなように
Meow, use my paws as you like...
完全降伏して
Surrendering completely.
crossing field
認めていた　臆病な過去
I had accepted my cowardly past.
わからないままに　怖がっていた
Not knowing anything, I was afraid.
後ろの自分が見せる　今を
The "me" behind me shows the present,
写す...
reflecting it...
いつも　空を　描いた
I always drew the sky.
ここはきっと　儚い心　乱して
This place will surely disturb my fleeting heart.
夢で高く跳んだ　身体は　どんな
No matter how the body that jumped high in a dream
不安まとっても　振り払っていく
is draped in anxiety, I'll shake it off.
眠る小さな想い　広がりだして
The small sleeping feelings begin to spread.
気づく弱い私　君がいれば
I realize my weakness, but if you're here,
暗い世界　強くいれた
I could stay strong in the dark world.
長い夢見る心は　そう永遠で
The heart dreaming a long dream is eternal.
I wanna always stay with you
I'll give you everything I have
探してた　導く光
The guiding light I was searching for.
触れれば　すべてを　思い出して
If I touch it, I'll remember everything.
かけがえのない　大切な今を
This irreplaceable, precious present...
くれる...
you give it to me...
目を閉じ　世界を知った
I closed my eyes and knew the world.
それはいつも　暖かい色に　痛くて
It was always painful in its warm colors.
繋ぐ確かな願い　重なり合って
The certain wishes we connect overlap,
見える迷いは　動き始めた
and the visible hesitation begins to move.
君を守りたくて　背を向けずは
Wanting to protect you, not turning my back,
浅い眠りの中　漂った
I drifted in a shallow sleep.
止まらない　約束だった
It was a promise that wouldn't stop.
二人信じた絆は　そう鮮明に
The bond we both believed in is so vivid.
I wanna always stay with you
I wanna hold you tight right now
I swear I'll wipe your tears away
I'll give you everything I have
いろはちゃん！
Iroha-chan!
ハッピーニューイヤー！
Happy New Year!
あれ？ あれ？ 違くない？ あれ？ なんか違くない？ あれ？
Wait, isn't that wrong? Huh? Something's not right.
間違えちゃった！ おまちがえ！
I made a mistake! My bad!
いろは聞いて、今ね...
Iroha, listen, just now...
ハッピーニューイヤーじゃなくて、メリークリスマス！って言って出てこようと思ってて...
Instead of Happy New Year, I was thinking of coming out saying Merry Christmas...
そいで、あ、違う違う、ハッピーバースデーじゃん！みたいな感じでやろうとしたんだけど...
And then, oh wait, no, it's Happy Birthday! I tried to do something like that...
ハッピーニューイヤーって言ってしまいました、いろは。
But I ended up saying Happy New Year, Iroha.
何も合ってないよ！
Nothing about that was right!
改めまして、いろはちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Once again, Iroha-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いろはが焼いてくれたクッキーがさ、もう美味しすぎてさ、あのバリバリ止まらなかったじゃんか。
The cookies you baked for me, Iroha, were so delicious, I just couldn't stop munching on them.
いっぱい食べてくれた！
You ate so many!
また食べたいなって思ってるんだけど、
I'm thinking I want to eat them again,
また焼いてくれる？
will you bake some more for me?
焼きますとも！
I definitely will!
わーい！ 嬉しい、ありがとう！
Yay! I'm so happy, thank you!
あとさあとさ、今日はさ、
Also, also... today...
あのさ、歌って踊りたいんだけどさ、一緒にさ、そっち行ってもいいかな？
I want to sing and dance together. Is it okay if I go over there?
やりますとも！
I'd love to!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃあ今からそっちに行くよ、いろは！
Then I'm coming over now, Iroha!
待ってろ、いろは！ 待ってろ！
Wait for me, Iroha! Wait for me!
ころね今からそっち行くからね！
Korone is coming over now!
待ってるでござる！
I'm waiting!
いろは待ってろ、いろは！
Iroha, wait for me!
きまぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
お得意の自己弁護 言い訳
Your favorite self-defense, your excuses
でもね さて
But then, well...
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
ごめんからのキスのパターンて感じ
The pattern of kissing after saying sorry
あーい
Ah...
いつか私だけ そんな夢見たこともあったけど
Once I even dreamed that I was the only one for you
寂しい時だけで お茶濁して もううんざりだわ
But you only reach out when you're lonely, and I'm tired of it
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The one you love is just yourself, isn't it?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
You really aren't interested in me at all
その話ももう聞き飽きたわ
I'm sick of hearing that same story over and over
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
To begin with, you basically have no interest in me
そうやってまた誤魔化してさ
And you're just deceiving me again like that
Be my boy わがまま過ぎるベイビー
Be my boy, you're such a selfish baby
抱きしめてよね
Just hold me tight, okay?
お先見はしょうがないな 甘え出ししょうがないな
Can't help looking ahead, can't help being pampered
泣いたって行かないでって言ったって変わらないや
Even if I cry or tell you not to go, it won't change anything
もう少しだけなら踊ってもいいかもな
Maybe I could dance just a little longer
トロけて トロけていたいよ
I want to melt, to just keep melting
どんなアピールも意味ないし 気づいてくれないけど
No matter how I try to appeal to you, you never notice
私が寂しい時だって 会いに来て
Even when I'm lonely, come and see me
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
どこがダメなら教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
You really aren't interested in me at all
携帯ばかり弄ってさ
You're just playing with your phone
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
To begin with, you basically have no interest in me
少し位期待させてよ
Give me at least a little bit of hope
Love me 私独り占めしてよベイビー
Love me, keep me all to yourself, baby
振り回さないで
Don't mess with my heart
ねえ Be my melty want you shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Hey, be my melty, want you, shall we dance? Let's dance
早く手を繋いで 最後に一つだけ
Quickly, hold my hand, and finally, just one more thing
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me so much that I could drown in it
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The one you love is just yourself, isn't it?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
You really aren't interested in me at all
その話ももう聞き飽きたわ
I'm sick of hearing that same story over and over
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
To begin with, you basically have no interest in me
そうやってまた誤魔化してさ
And you're just deceiving me again like that
結末ならさ 覚悟はできてるの
I'm already prepared for how this ends
きまぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
おたんじょうびおめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
失礼しまーす！
Excuse me!
ホロライブ2期生の大空スバルです、しゅば！
I'm Oozora Subaru from Hololive 2nd Gen, Shuba!
おっす！いろは殿、お誕生日おめでとう！
Ossu! Iroha-dono, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
めでたいめでたいめでたい、
Celebrate, celebrate, celebrate,
めでたいですね。
it's celebratory.
今日はいろは殿の応援に駆けつけました！
I came here today to cheer for Iroha-dono!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
もうやっぱりね、いろは殿といえばね、最初は「だ、大丈夫かな、この子」
Well, talking about Iroha-dono, at first I was like "I-is she going to be okay?"
なんかすごいふわふわしてるし、大丈夫か、ジャンプキング。
She's so airy, is she okay with Jump King?
そんな感じで大丈夫？みたいな感じだったんですけども。
Is it okay like that? That's how it felt.
懐かしい。
Nostalgic.
もうね、今やもう、すごく立派になってというような感じで。
But now, she's grown so much.
スバルママ〜！
Subaru-mama~!
いろは殿は本当に真っ直ぐで頑張り屋さんなので、
Iroha-dono is really straightforward and a hard worker,
これからもね、そのままの素敵ないろは殿でいてください。
so please keep being the wonderful Iroha-dono you are.
そしてですね、いろは殿にとってこの一年が素敵な一年になりますように。
And I hope this year will be a wonderful one for you.
影ながら応援しております。
I'm rooting for you from the sidelines.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
あ、ではね、ちょっとね、
Oh, well, a little bit,
もうちょっとね、近くでね、いろは殿を応援したいと思いまーす！
I want to cheer for Iroha-dono from a bit closer!
お祝いしに今からそちらに向かいまーす！
I'm heading over there right now to celebrate!
それでは、ワープしちゃうぞー！
Well then, I'm gonna warp!
ワーーープ！
Waaaaarp!
おおー！
Ooh!
せーの！
Ready, set!
トーーーッ！
Tooooh!
神のまにまに / 作詞・作曲・編曲：れるりり
At the Mercy of the Gods / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: rerulili
思い通りにいかないことだらけ
Full of things that don't go as planned
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
Hopelessly feeling self-hatred
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
From the pain and sorrow of the eight million gods
逃げ込める場所探してる
Searching for a place to escape to
いっそ岩の隙間に引きこもって
Might as well shut myself in a gap between rocks
月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
Ignoring both the moon and the sun, let's sleep
生まれてきたことの意味なんて
The meaning of being born into this world
知らない わかんないよ
I don't know, I don't understand
でもそんな風に思えるってこと
But the fact that you can feel that way
それは君がもっともっと素敵になれる
It's because you have the power to become
力がるって教えてるんだよ
Much, much more wonderful, that's what it's telling you
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods, as they command
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth
飲めや歌えやどんちゃん騒ぎ
Drink, sing, and make a ruckus
たまにゃそんなのもいいもんだ
Occasionally, that's a good thing
そうさ 北も南も右も左も
That's right, north, south, right, or left
なんだかんだ地球を愛してる
In the end, we all love the Earth
どろんこだけど歩いて行ける
Even if covered in mud, we can keep walking
まだまだ先は長いさ
The road ahead is still long
ただ正しい人でいたいだけ
Just want to be a righteous person
きっと誰もがそう願っているけど
I'm sure everyone wishes for that
八百万の心の醜さに
But by the ugliness of the eight million hearts
苦しめられる毎日さ
I'm tormented every day
僕が生まれてきたこと
The fact that I was born
奇跡と言えば聞こえはいいけど
Sounds nice if you call it a miracle
それはきっと偶然にすぎなくて
But it's surely nothing more than a coincidence
やっぱり意味なんてないさ
After all, there's no meaning
でも例えば君にいじわるをする
But for example, the existence of those
奴がいるなら
Who are mean to you
それは君がとっても素敵な人だって
It's because you're such a wonderful person
教えてるんだよ
That's what it's telling you
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods, as they command
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth
僕が笑って
I'll laugh
君も笑えば
And if you laugh too
許せないことなんてないよ
There's nothing that can't be forgiven
そうさ 男も女も 恋しかるべき
That's right, men and women should fall in love
そんなふうに地球は回ってる
That's how the Earth keeps turning
どろんこだけど歩いて行こう
Even if covered in mud, let's keep walking
まだまだ先は長いさ
The road ahead is still long
本当に大事なものなんて
Things that are truly important
案外くだらないことの中に
Are surprisingly found within
あるよ
pointless things.
ときにはみんなで馬鹿騒ぎ
Sometimes, let's all make a huge ruckus
裸踊りで
dancing naked,
大笑い
laughing out loud.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods, as they command
もっともっと自分を愛せるよ
You'll be able to love yourself even more
鏡を見てごらんよ
Take a look in the mirror
もうわかるでしょ
You see it now, don't you?
みんなを照らす光さ
You're the light that shines on everyone
そうさ 神のまにまに
That's right, at the mercy of the gods
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
ア・イ・ウ・エ・オ　地球を愛してる
A-I-U-E-O, I love the Earth
花も咲かそう　大きな花を
Let's make flowers bloom too, big flowers
天まで届くくらいの
Reaching all the way to the heavens
La la la...
深海少女
Deep Sea Girl
悲しみの海に沈んだ私　目を開けるのも億劫
Sinking into a sea of sadness,
it's even a chore to open my eyes
このままどこまでも落ちて行き
Falling further and further like this,
誰にも見つけられないのかな
I wonder if no one will ever find me
どこへ向かい、何をすれば？
Where am I headed, what should I do?
ふと差し込む一筋の光
Suddenly, a single ray of light shines in
手を伸ばせば届きそうだけど
It feels like I could reach it
if I stretched out my hand, but...
波にさらわれて見失った
...it was swept away by the waves and lost
あれは一体なんだったのかな
I wonder what that really was
あたたかくて眩しかったの
It was so warm and dazzling
無意識のカウンターイルミネーション
Unconscious counter-illumination
嘘つきはだれ？
Who is the liar?
深海少女　まだまだ沈む
Deep sea girl, still sinking,
暗闇の彼方へ閉じこもる
shutting herself away beyond the darkness
深海少女　だけど知りたい
Deep sea girl, but I want to know,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because I found the person my heart is drawn to
昼も夜もなかったこの場所
This place had neither day nor night,
なのに眠れない夜は続く
and yet, the sleepless nights continue
自由の羽を大きく広げて
Spreading your wings of freedom wide,
泳ぐあなたは綺麗でした
you were so beautiful as you swam
そしてまた光は降り注ぐ
And then the light pours in again,
見とれていた目が合った
I was staring and our eyes met
気づいてこっちを振り返るあなたに
To you, who noticed and turned back to look at me,
嘘つきな私
I was a liar
深海少女　わざわざ沈む
Deep sea girl, sinking on purpose,
暗闇の中に赤い頬
red cheeks within the darkness
深海少女　裸の心を
Deep sea girl, the courage to show...
見せる勇気　黒い海がまだ許さない
...my naked heart, the black sea won't allow it yet
こんなに服は汚れてしまった
My clothes have become so dirty,
笑顔も醜く歪んでいった
even my smile became hideously distorted
誰にも合わせる顔なんてないの
I have no face to show anyone,
もう放っておいてよ！
just leave me alone!
声にならない気持ちが溢れて溶けた
The feelings that wouldn't become words
overflowed and melted
次の瞬間、君が突然　姿を消した
The next moment, you suddenly disappeared
心配性の彼女は焦る
The worrying girl gets impatient,
闇が彼を隠しひとりきり
the darkness hides him and she's all alone
限界少女　その手を伸ばす
Limit girl, she stretches out her hand,
ほらね、君も素敵な色を隠してた
see, you were hiding wonderful colors too
深海少女　腕を引かれる
Deep sea girl, her arm is pulled,
歌う祝福のマリンスノー
the marine snow of singing blessings
深海少女　もっと知りたい
Deep sea girl, I want to know more,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because I found the person my heart is drawn to
この海を出て、今飛び立つの
I'm leaving this sea, and taking flight now
いろはちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Iroha-chan, happy birthday!
あずき、ハッピーバースデー！ありがとう！
AZKi, happy birthday! Thank you!
AZKiです。
I'm AZKi.
えー、いろはちゃんとは、ま、今年も、あずいろで歌ってみたを出したりとか
Um, with Iroha-chan, well, this year too,
we've released "AzuIro" cover videos and such,
歌枠コラボしてみたり
did karaoke stream collaborations,
個人的に、えー、ちいかわグッズを一緒に買いに行ったり
personally, um, went to buy Chiikawa goods together,
してお昼ご飯にも行ったり、いつも仲良くしてくれてありがとう
and went to lunch; thank you for
always being such a good friend.
えー、去年ね、一周年ライブ...
Um, last year, the first anniversary live...
いろはちゃんの１周年のライブの時に歌った桜ロックも２人歌声が合っていたし...
In the Sakura Rock we sang during your 1st anniversary live, our voices matched well too...
なんと、この後も一緒に歌っちゃう、歌っちゃうのか！
And, we're going to sing together after this too, are we really going to sing!
ということで、これからもぜひ「あずいろ」よろしくお願いします！
So, please continue to support "Azuiro" from now on!
あずいろをよろしくお願いします！
Please support Azuiro!
ということで、今からワープしてそっちに向かいます！
With that, I'm going to warp and head over there now!
あずきちゃん待ってるよー！
AZKi-chan, I'll be waiting!
あずいくよー！
Azu is going!
sister's noise / 作詞・作曲・編曲：八木沼悟志
sister's noise / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Satoshi Yaginuma
誰よりも近くにいた
I was closer to you than anyone else
その声は聴こえなくて
but I couldn't hear that voice
刻み続けていた時の中で
In the time that kept ticking away
やっと君に逢えたから
I finally met you
sister's noise　捜し続ける
sister's noise, I keep searching
彷徨う心の場所を
for the place of my wandering heart
感じあったこの想いは
These feelings we shared
誰にも壊せないから！
because no one can break them!
街はひそやかに
The city was quietly
君を隠してた
hiding you
たどり着いた場所
The place I arrived at
蘇るあの記憶
those memories come back to life
繰り返されてた
The truth that was being
真実は遠く
repeated is far away
君のその痛み
Without noticing
気づけないまま
your pain
あの日託したその夢が
Even if the dream I entrusted that day
私を切り裂いても
tears me apart
何よりも大切な希望だけ
I will believe only in the
信じ抜いて
most important hope of all
自分らしく生きること
I want to tell you more than anything
何よりも伝えたくて
to live as yourself
上書きし続けてく悲しみの痛み
If the pain of sadness that
その意味を刻むなら
continues to be overwritten carves its meaning
sister's noise　いま届けるよ
sister's noise, I'll deliver it now
涙さえ力にして
turning even tears into strength
繋がりあう強さだけが
Only the strength of our connection
すべてを撃ち抜いてゆく
will pierce through everything
夕暮れの放課後
After school at dusk
いつもの街並み
the usual streetscape
ふと見上げた空
The sky I suddenly looked up at
思い出す優しさを
remembering your kindness
君のまなざしが
Your gaze
気づかせてくれた
made me realize
弱さ認める勇気の
The strength of the courage
強さを
to admit weakness
あたたかな君のその手が
Your warm hand
私を導いてく
leads me on
何よりも守りたい希望が
Because the hope I want to protect
闇を貫くから
more than anything pierces through the darkness
抱きしめた熱い想い
Because the passionate feelings I embraced
この世界を照らすから
will light up this world
走り続け　捜し続けていた
Keep running, the dream you've been searching for
君の夢が動き出す
starts to move
sister's noise　響き始める
sister's noise starts to resound
高らかな命の意味
the meaning of a ringing life
混ぜ合ってるかけがえない絆は
Because the irreplaceable bonds we share
壊せないから！
can't be broken!
自分らしく生きること
I want to tell you more than anything
何よりも伝えたくて
to live as yourself
上書きし続けてく悲しみの痛み
If the pain of sadness that
その意味を刻むなら
continues to be overwritten carves its meaning
誰よりも近くにいた
I was closer to you than anyone else
その声は聴こえなくて
but I couldn't hear that voice
刻み続けていた時の中で
In the time that kept ticking away
やっと君に逢えたから
I finally met you
sister's noise　捜し続ける
sister's noise, I keep searching
彷徨う心の場所を
for the place of my wandering heart
感じあった同じ笑顔
I'll definitely protect
必ず守ってみせる
the same smile we shared
もう誰にも壊せないから！
Because no one can break it anymore!
はい！というわけで...
Yes! And so...
ここでお届け、怒涛の歌とダンスを、お届けさせていただきましたでござる！
And here, I've just presented you with a flurry of songs and dances de-gozaru!
そしてね、あの、深海少女の時に、お着替えして、ちょっと、紹介するタイミングなかったんですけど...
And, when I changed during "Deep Sea Girl," I didn't have time to introduce it, but...
じゃっじゃーん！ブライト衣装でござる！
Ta-da! It's the "Bright" outfit de-gozaru!
なんだかんだね、自分の配信で着るのは初めての、この衣装、エキスポぶり... でござるな。どうですか？
Somehow, this is the first time I've worn this outfit on my own stream since the EXPO... de-gozaru na. How is it?
そしてなんと今回はですね、さっきまでスパッツ履いてたんですけど、今、初めてスカート履いてみました。ちょっとスースーするでござるな。
And surprisingly, I was wearing spats until a moment ago, but now for the first time, I tried wearing a skirt. It feels a bit breezy de-gozaru na.
あんま慣れないんですけど、どうですか？どうですか？
I'm not really used to it, but how is it? How is it?
スカートもいいでござるな。このあとはね、せっかくなんで、このスカートで歌って踊って行きたいと思います。
A skirt is also nice de-gozaru na. Since it's a rare occasion, I'd like to sing and dance in this skirt from now on.
可愛いでござるよな。そしてね、皆様、何曲も聴いて見ていただいたと思うんですが...
It's cute, isn't it? And, you've watched several songs...
ステージもいい感じで、気づいた人いるかな？この中にですね、なんとポコべー隠れてるんですけど、気づいた隊士さん、いますかー？
The stage looks great too, did anyone notice? Surprisingly, Pokobe is hiding in here! Are there any squires who noticed?
いるかー？今、コメント見てんだけど、いるー？
Anyone? I'm looking at the comments now, any?
スカートも可愛い？ありがとう！センキュー！
The skirt is also cute? Thank you! Thank you!
え、いるでござるかー？あ、いない？いや、いるんだな実はポコべーが！
Eh, are you there? Ah, not there? No, actually Pokobe is here!
ポコべーがね、あの辺にね... ちょっと待って、あの辺に、あれ？なんか、ポコべー、なんか、様子がおかしいでござるな。
Pokobe is, around that area... wait, around there, huh? Wait, Pokobe... something seems strange de-gozaru na.
あれ？ポコべー？ポコべー？
Huh? Pokobe? Pokobe?
うわっ、ポコべー！いつも何か起きるポコべーに！うわあ！
Uwah! Pokobe! Something always happens to Pokobe! Whoa!
ポコべー、お前、動けるようになったのか！？え、ポコべー？え、ポコべー？ポコべー！
Pokobe, you... have you become able to move?! Eh, Pokobe? Pokobe? Pokobe!
そうだね、足遅いからドローン乗らなきゃいつも行けないんだよね。そうだよね！え、ポコべー？え、動いてるよね？
Right, your legs are slow, so you always have to ride a drone to get anywhere, right? That's right! Eh, Pokobe? You're moving, right?
あ、あ、みんなポコべーが来るぞ！ポコべー！ポコべー！
Ah, everyone, Pokobe is coming! Pokobe! Pokobe!
ポコべー！ポコべー！
Pokobe! Pokobe!
ひゃあ！ポコべー、こっち向いて！え、めっちゃこっち来るじゃん！え、ポコべー、お前、動けるようになったんか？
Kyaa! Pokobe, look this way! Whoa, it's coming right at us! Eh, Pokobe, you've become able to move?
え、来る、来る！来る、来る！ポコべー！ポコべー！
Eh, it's coming! It's coming! Pokobe! Pokobe!
え、ということで、まさかのですね、ポコべーが来てくれました！ポコべー！
So, surprisingly, Pokobe has come! Pokobe!
え、自由に動けるようになったでござるかポコべー。そっか、よかったね！え、せっかくじゃあ、一緒にちょっと、写真でもいかがですか、ポコべーさん？
Eh, you can move freely now, Pokobe? I see, that's great! Since you're here, how about we take a photo together, Pokobe-san?
え、え。
Yeah, yeah.
いやー、まさか最後にゲストとして動けるようになったポコべーが来てくれるとは！イエーイ！
I didn't expect Pokobe, who can now move, to come as a guest at the end! Yay!
ポコべー、ちょっと、肩の後ろ行こうか。いくよ、せーの、ほっ！せーの、ほっ！せーの、ほっ！
Pokobe, come behind my shoulder. Ready, hop! Ready, hop! Ready, hop!
え、ポコべー、すごいね！動けるようになったね！めっちゃ、みんな、めっちゃ、でかっ、て言われてるぞポコべー。でかって。
Whoa, Pokobe, you're amazing! You can move now! Everyone's saying you're huge, Pokobe. Huge.
でかい？あ、でかくない。あ、可愛いって、ポコべー。
Huge? Ah, not huge. Ah, they're saying you're cute, Pokobe.
あー、可愛い！そうだよね、可愛い、でござるな。皆様のポコべー拍手！可愛い！あ、可愛いねポコべー。
Ah, cute! Right, you're cute de-gozaru na. A round of applause for Pokobe! Cute! You're so cute, Pokobe.
ね、せっかくね、今日ポコべーとね、ついにステージに立てたということで、何気に動く、ポコべー、動けるようになったの初めてでござるよな。
Since I've finally stood on stage with Pokobe today... it's actually the first time Pokobe has been able to move.
そうだよね、嬉しいよね？そうだよね。じゃあ、さ、せっかく来たので、ポコべー、今回初、一緒に踊っちゃいますか？
Right? You're happy? Right. Then, since you're here, Pokobe, for the first time, shall we dance together?
踊りますか？おおー！ということで、じゃあ次の曲はですね、ポコべーと一緒に踊って、風真が歌いたいと思います！
Shall we? Oh! So, for the next song, Kazama will sing while dancing with Pokobe!
よし！というわけで、ちょっとポコべーがね、準備中でございます。ポコべー、準備はいいでござるか？
Alright! So, Pokobe is preparing now. Pokobe, are you ready de-gozaru ka?
お、良さそうなので、それでは、一緒に頑張って行きたいと思います！それでは聴いてください。何が悪い。
Oh, looks like it! Well then, we'll do our best together! Please listen: "Nani ga Warui."
悩んでなくて何が悪い？ 青春で何が悪い？
What's wrong with not worrying? What's wrong with youth?
なにが悪い
What's Wrong
作詞・作曲：北澤ゆうほ
Lyrics & Composition: Yuuho Kitazawa
ねえどうして止まらない 止められないリズムが体の中 響いている
Hey, why won't it stop? An unstoppable rhythm is echoing inside me.
イヤホンから流れるメロディーだけが 僕をホッとさせてくれた
Only the melody flowing from my earphones gave me relief.
赤い色に染まる空 僕の心は何色だろう
The sky stained in red... what color is my heart?
教えて 僕はどこへ向かえばいい
Tell me, where should I go?
ずっと探してた 何かをいつか失くしてしまうものばかりでも
Even if everything I've been looking for will eventually be lost...
強く刻んでいこう 惨めな夜も変わらない想いを今
Let's strongly carve it in now, these feelings that won't change even on miserable nights.
成り止まったって何が悪い
What's wrong with stopping?
青春で何が悪い
What's wrong with being youthful?
ねぇどおして触れてみたい触れられない未来から
Hey, why, from the untouchable future I want to touch...
今日も僕を迷わせてる
...you still leave me lost today.
みんなは知らないあのバンドの曲
That band's song that nobody knows,
君にだけ聴かせたいんだ
I want to let only you hear it.
何もかも悲しいほど綺麗で満開さ
Everything is so beautiful it's sad, in full bloom,
俯く待ったよ
I've waited with my head bowed.
机の上にはない僕らの答え
Our answer isn't on the desk,
そっと隠してた大切な言葉を
the precious words I've been hiding...
今叫ぶんだ
I'll shout them now!
例えば人と違う夢描くこと
Like dreaming a different dream from others,
君と喧嘩したこと
or having a fight with you.
すべて最高なプレゼント
They're all the best presents,
大人になった僕へのプレゼント
presents for the me who has grown up.
ねえ正真正銘何が悪い
Hey, what's truly wrong with it?
教えて僕はどこへ向かえばいい
Tell me, where should I head to?
心は凍んないだ大切はここにある
My heart isn't frozen, the important things are here.
心臓のうるさく僕に伝えたんだ
The loudness of my heart told me,
急がずにその先へ
without rushing, to the path ahead.
滲まない夜も変わらないもの
Even in nights that don't blur, some things don't change.
ああもっとあとで言えた日の笑顔を
Ah, the smile of the day when I could say more later,
成り止まったって何が悪い
What's wrong with stopping?
青春で何が悪い
What's wrong with being youthful?
はい。というわけでですね
Yes. And so,
ぽこべぇと一緒に「何が悪い」踊らせていただきました！
I danced to "Nani ga Warui" with Pokobe!
ぽこべぇ、ありがとー！
Pokobe, thank you!
いやー、楽しかった？ぽこべぇ
Man, was it fun? Pokobe.
あぁー良かった！
Ah, that's good!
何気にこういう機会なかったからね
We didn't really have many opportunities like this,
風真も一緒に踊れて楽しかったでござる！
so I had fun dancing with you too!
今日は来てくれてありがとう、ぽこべぇ
Thanks for coming today, Pokobe.
そして、どうやら、なんかこの生誕ライブ、トレンドが、なんか2位みたいで！
And apparently, it seems this birthday live is trending at #2!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
日曜のこの時間まで毎回決まったあのトレンドがあるんですけど
There's always that fixed trend around this time on Sundays,
その忙しい中、トレンド2位まで皆がいっぱい呟いてくれてありがとうございます
but in the midst of that, thank you everyone for
tweeting so much and getting us to #2!
あとでね、風真もライブ終わったらゆっくり皆との感想見させてもらうので
I'll take my time to look at everyone's feedback after the live,
まだまだいっぱいツイートよろしくお願いします！
so please keep those tweets coming!
さて、ぽこべぇと一緒に踊って楽しかったね
Now then, it was fun dancing with Pokobe.
そろそろ1回戻んないとね、ぽこべぇ
It's about time for you to head back, Pokobe.
そうだよね。じゃあ、皆にバイバイってして
Right. Well then, say bye-bye to everyone.
バイバ～イ！
Bye-bye~!
あ、可愛いね、ぽこべぇ！ありがとう！
Ah, so cute, Pokobe! Thank you!
じゃあ先にね、道場に戻ってゆっくりしててくださいね
Then go back to the dojo and take it easy.
はーい。ぽこべぇありがとねー！
Okay. Thanks, Pokobe!
おぉ、そ、そういう消え方なんだ。はははは！
Oh, so that's how you disappear. Hahaha!
あぁーぽこべぇ、そういう消え方すんだ。ちょっとドロン、ドロンだったね、今、完全に
Ah, Pokobe, so that's how you vanish.
It was a total "poof," a "doron," just now.
ぽこべぇ忍者なのかな？あ、違うよ、風真は侍だけどね
Is Pokobe a ninja? Ah, no, I'm the samurai though.
というわけで、楽しい時間はあっという間でござるな
In any case, fun times really do fly by.
なんと次の曲がね、その、すみません、あの、最後の曲になってしまうんでござるが
Believe it or not, the next song... sorry,
will be the last one.
えーーー今来たばっかり！
Ehh--- I just got here!
と、その前に、やっぱりありますよ。はい、告知です！
But before that, of course, we have this. Yes, an announcement!
それではいきますよ！せーの、ドジャン！
Here we go! Ready, set, ta-da!
まず、グッズが出てます！イェーイ！
First off, there's merchandise! Yay!
風真いろは誕生日記念2023グッズ！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration 2023 Merchandise!
はい、今回もですね、可愛いイラストと共に可愛いグッズをたくさんご用意させていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Yes, this time too, we've prepared plenty of cute items
with lovely illustrations. Thank you very much!
それでは順番にご紹介していきましょう。はい、じゃあ最初はこちら！
Let's introduce them one by one. Okay, first up is this!
絵皿！いやー可愛いーでござるよな
An illustrated plate! Man, it's so cute, isn't it?
今回ですね、えっと、リズ先生にイラストお願いさせていただきました
This time, well, we asked Liz-sensei to do the illustrations.
わーい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
風真のね、あのファンの皆さん、隊士さんたちはよく風真のレシピを真似してクッキーとか作ってくださっていると思うので、
For Kazama's fans, the Taishi-san, who often follow my recipes to make cookies and such...
それをお召し上がりに使っていただいたり...
...you can use this plate to eat them...
...飾ってもね、可愛いと思うので、
...and I think it'll be cute to display it too,
ぜひね、いろんな用途でお皿使ってください。風真も使います！
so please use this plate for various purposes. Kazama will use it too!
これにガトーショコラ置くんだ、風真。
Kazama is going to put gateau chocolat on this.
はい。じゃあ次いきますね。こちらです。はい！
Okay, moving on to the next one. It's this! Here!
そして同じイラストでコースターご用意させていただきました。
And we've prepared a coaster with the same illustration.
なんかあの、お皿の時ってコースターって...そうなんです！
It's like, you have a plate, then you need a coaster... Exactly!
この後もどんどん見ていただきますが、皆殿、今回はですね、
As you'll see more of this as we go on, but everyone...
日常生活で一緒に使っていただけるようなものをたくさん用意しております。
...this time, I've prepared many things that you can use together in your daily lives.
コースターもですね、可愛いデザインになっておりますので、
The coaster also has a cute design,
ぜひ学校、職場、使えるところでね、
so please use it at school, work, or wherever you can,
お家でもどんどん使っていただけると嬉しいです！
and I'd be happy if you used it a lot at home too!
それでは次！次はこちら！
Alright, next! Next is this!
さまてる先生にイラスト描いていただきました、
With an illustration drawn by Samateru-sensei,
こちらビッグタオルでござる。可愛い！
it's the big towel de gozaru. Cute!
もうね、スポーツ、お風呂上がり、もう飾る、何でも用途あり！
For sports, after a bath, or just for display, it has so many uses!
本当にね、皆殿の生活に役立てていただければと思います。
I really hope you can find it useful in your daily lives.
風真もいっぱい使うぞ！ありがとうございます！
Kazama will use it a lot too! Thank you!
そして皆殿、このイラスト、ちょっと覚えておいてね。このイラスト！
And everyone, please remember this illustration. This one!
よく目に焼き付けておいてくださいね！噛みまみた。はい、じゃあ次いきます。
Burn it into your eyes! I bit my tongue. Okay, moving on.
はい。次がタンブラーです！
Next is the tumbler!
なんとね、蓋付きでございます。あのお水は零さない仕様になっておりますので。
It even comes with a lid. It's designed so that water won't spill.
コースターと合わせてね、ぜひ使っていただけるととってもとっても嬉しいです！
I'd be very happy if you used it together with the coaster!
ぜひたくさん使ってください。こちらもポコベデザインです。お願いします。
Please use it a lot. This also has a Pokobe design. Please look forward to it.
そしてそして、今回も記念ボイスあります！
And also, we have memorial voices this time too!
大変お待たせしました。風真いろはのシステムボイス12種ということで。
Sorry to keep you waiting. It's the Kazama Iroha System Voice Set, with 12 types.
以前からですね、いろはちゃんのシステムボイス欲しいなっていうことでお声をいただいておりました。
I've been hearing people say they want an Iroha system voice set for a while now.
今回ですね、12種類頑張ってパソコンのシステムボイス撮らせていただきました。めっちゃ頑張った！
This time, I worked hard and recorded 12 types of PC system voices. I really did my best!
いや、なんかね、ユニークで楽しいシステムボイスがですね、いっぱい揃っておりますので、
I've got a lot of unique and fun system voices ready,
ぜひね、皆殿のパソコンにインストールして、
so please install them on your PCs,
あの、毎日の生活の彩りにしていただければと思います。
and use them to add some color to your daily lives.
起動するたびに風真の声が聞こえるようになるし、
You'll hear Kazama's voice every time you start it up,
シャットダウンするたびに風真の声が聞こえるようになります。ぜひたくさん使ってください。
and every time you shut it down. I hope you use them a lot.
はい。そしてフルセットがこのようになっております。はい、こんな感じで！
And here is the full set. It's like this!
そしてフルセット購入特典でですね、今回もチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてまいりまして、
As a full set purchase bonus, we have a cheki-style bromide card again this time,
なんと数量限定で、今回風真いろは、直筆サインをですね、
and in limited quantities, Kazama Iroha will be providing handwritten signatures again.
ありがたいことにね、また書かせていただくことになりましたので。ありがとうございます。
I'm grateful to have the opportunity to do this again. Thank you so much.
たくさんね、皆殿の手元に風真の直筆サインが届くといいなと思っておりますので、
I hope Kazama's handwritten signatures reach many of you,
ぜひぜひ直筆サイン欲しいなって思ってくれている隊士さんたちはご購入いただけると嬉しいです。
so for the Taishi-san who want a handwritten signature, I'd be happy if you purchased it.
そしてなんとこちらですね、フルセット購入特典でボイスも付いております。
And what's more, a bonus voice is also included with the full set.
あの、風真がね、いつもちょっとボイスは、先日のはジューンブライドとかもそうなんですけど、
Well, Kazama... as for voices, like with the June Bride one the other day...
ちょっとあんまり、得意じゃないんですけど、今回は一緒に誕生日をお家でお祝いするっていうシチュエーションで...
I'm not really good at them, but this time, it's a situation where we celebrate my birthday at home...
...頑張らせていただきましたので、よかったら聴いてもらえると嬉しいです。ちょっと恥ずかしいけど頑張りました。
...so I did my best, and I'd be happy if you listened to it. It's a bit embarrassing, but I gave it my all.
よろしくお願いします。はい！そして！そしてですよ！
Thank you. Yes! And! And there's more!
まだ実はあります。実はおるんです。それではいきますよ。せーの、ドン！
There's actually still more. There really is. Here we go. One, two, boom!
はい！風真いろは公式LINEスタンプ発売決定でござる！
Yes! The official Kazama Iroha LINE stamps are set to be released!
いやお待たせしました！みんな欲しいって言ってくれてたから、作っていました。
Sorry to have kept you waiting! You all said you wanted them, so I was making them.
はい、イラストはさめあんこ先生にお願いしました。ありがとうございます。
The illustrations were done by Sameanko-sensei. Thank you very much.
いやこちらもですね、すごく可愛いスタンプになっておりますので、ぜひぜひ皆殿にたくさん使っていただいて、
These are also very cute stamps, so please use them a lot, everyone.
どうやら21時ぐらいまでには買えるようになっているということなので、ぜひ使っていただけると嬉しいです。
They should be available to buy by around 21:00, so I'd be happy if you used them.
風真も使います！よろしくお願いします。待ってた？ありがとう！ぜひいっぱい使ってくださいね。
Kazama will use them too! Thank you. Were you waiting for them? Thank you! Please use them a lot.
そしてこの後21時15分頃から、メンバーシップ限定のアフターライブがあります。
And after this, from around 21:15, there will be a membership-only after-live.
今回もですね、頑張って、まだアフターライブでも歌って踊りますので、
I'll be working hard to sing and dance more during the after-live,
まだメンバーシップ入ってないよって方はぜひ加入していただけると嬉しいです。そしてお知らせがもう一つあります。
so if you haven't joined the membership yet, I'd be happy if you did. And one more announcement.
今回メンバーシップ限定で、今回のライブで使用した風真のソロの歌唱曲のバックスクリーンイラストの...
Exclusively for members, high-res background illustrations used during Kazama's solo songs...
...高画質バージョンを配布させていただきます。イェーイ！
...will be distributed. Yay!
全6種類、6名のイラストレーター様にですね、書き上げていただいた風真いろはのイラストになっております。
There are 6 types in total, illustrations of Kazama Iroha drawn by 6 different illustrators.
書き上げていただいた風真いろはのイラストになっております。
These are illustrations of Kazama Iroha drawn for this live.
こちらもぜひね、皆殿の手元に置いていただければと思います。
I hope you'll all keep these close to you.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to them!
はい。以上が、告知でございました。ふう、いっぱいあったね。
Okay. That's all for the announcements. Whew, there were a lot!
喜んでもらえたかな？
I hope you're happy with them!
風真もね、今日のためにいろいろ準備してきたから、
Kazama also prepared many things for today,
こうやってみんなに発表できて嬉しいです。
so I'm glad I could announce them to everyone like this.
それでは、最後の一曲...にいきたいところなんですが、
Now, I'd like to move on to the final song...
その前に、ちょっとだけお話しさせてください。
...but before that, please let me talk for just a bit.
改めて、今日は見に来てくれて本当にありがとうございます。
Once again, thank you so much for coming to see me today.
風真、ホロライブに入ってから、いろんなことがあったけど、
Since Kazama joined Hololive, a lot has happened,
こうして誕生日をみんなとお祝いできるのが、
but being able to celebrate my birthday with all of you like this...
本当に幸せです。
really makes me happy.
隊士さん、そしてホロライブの仲間、スタッフさん、
To the Taishi-san, my Hololive friends, the staff,
みんなのおかげで、風真はここにいられます。
and everyone, it's thanks to you that Kazama is here.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
それでは、聞いてください。最後の曲です。
Now, please listen. This is the last song.
...ありますので、
...there will be,
この後21時にコミュニティ投稿ちゃんとされるはず、
a community post will be made properly at 21:00 after this.
予約と和解しているはず、
It should be scheduled and ready.
なので是非ですね、あの、待ってる間に
So please, while you're waiting,
ダウンロードしていただけると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could download it.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
はい、というわけでドトーのご紹介でした。
All right, that was a whirlwind of introductions.
いや、もう、本当にね、本当にあっという間すぎて、
Man, it's really... it's really gone by so fast,
どうしようって気持ちでいっぱいなんですけども。
that I'm just filled with the feeling of 'What should I do?'
誕生日2回目、皆と一緒に迎えることができて、
Being able to celebrate my 2nd birthday with everyone,
とってもとっても嬉しいです。
makes me very, very happy.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
本当に色々ね、数多く3Dライブやらせていただいておりますが、
I've really done many 3D lives in various ways,
また成長した姿を見せれたでしょうか？
but was I able to show you how I've grown?
まだね、最初から見てないよって方は、
If you haven't seen it from the beginning,
またこのアーカイブになってからも最初から見ていただいて、
please watch it from the beginning once it's archived,
もう見たけどもう一回見たいって方もね、
and for those who've seen it but want to watch again,
きっといらっしゃると信じて、もう一回見て、
I believe there are some, so please watch it again.
そしてね、他の3Dライブのアーカイブとも見比べて、
And then, compare it with my other 3D live archives,
風真がどういう風に成長してきたか、
and see how Kazama has grown.
今一度見ていただけると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could take another look.
それでは次、最後の曲になります。
Now, for the next and final song.
心を込めて、歌って踊りますので、
I'll sing and dance with all my heart,
最後まで聴いてください！
so please listen until the end!
愛言葉Ⅱ
Aikotoba II
皆、今日は最後までライブ見てくれて、
Everyone, thank you for watching the live until the end today.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
一緒に誕生日お祝いしてもらえて、
Being able to have my birthday celebrated together,
すごく嬉しかったです！
made me very happy!
これからもよろしくねー！
Please continue to support me!
いつかの歌も今や
The song from some time ago is now,
100万才になって
a million years old,
僕の何万倍も
growing older
年をとっちゃって
many ten thousands times more than me.
いつのまにか僕も
Before I knew it, even I,
5歳の誕生日
celebrating my 5th birthday,
君は僕よりも
know about me
僕のこと知っているんだ
better than I do myself.
愛も恋も僕も君も
Love, romance, me, you,
好きも嫌いも全部
likes, dislikes, everything,
嘘も本当も
Lies and truths,
まだまだ歌うね
I'll keep on singing.
今これまでのありがとう
Now, thank you for everything until now.
これからもありがとう
Thank you for the future as well.
君に伝えたいことは
The thing I want to tell you
それだけなんだけど
is only that, but...
なかなか上手く言えなくて
I can't seem to say it well,
傷付けて泣いちゃってごめん
I'm sorry for hurting you and making you cry.
5年分の感謝
Five years worth of gratitude,
救世主は君のありがとう
The savior is your 'thank you'.
3と9をかけると
When you multiply 3 and 9,
27になるの
it becomes 27.
僕を何倍しても
No matter how many times you multiply me,
君がいるよ
you're there.
それだけでこの先
Just with that, from now on,
なんだって出来るから
I can do anything,
どこへだって行こう
so let's go anywhere.
君を連れて歌を歌って
Taking you along, singing songs,
愛も恋も僕も君も
Love, romance, me, you,
好きも嫌いも全部
likes, dislikes, everything,
嘘も本当も
Lies and truths,
まだまだ歌うね
I'll keep on singing.
君がいて…
You're here...
バカ。
Dummy.
僕がいて…
I'm here...
バカ。
Dummy.
バカじゃない大切な
It's not being a dummy,
ことなんだよ…バカ。
it's something important... dummy.
今これまでのありがとう
Now, thank you for everything until now.
これからもありがとう
Thank you for the future as well.
君に伝えたいことは
The thing I want to tell you
それだけなんだけど
is only that, but...
なかなか上手く言えなくて
I can't seem to say it well,
傷付けて泣いちゃってごめん
I'm sorry for hurting you and making you cry.
5年分の感謝
Five years worth of gratitude,
救世主は君のありがとう
The savior is your 'thank you'.
ハロー また出会えたね
Hello, we met again.
サヨナラ また別れて
Goodbye, we part again,
ハロー また同じ場所で
Hello, in the same place again,
出会えたんだ
we were able to meet.
愛言葉II
Ai Kotoba II
今が好きで　愛してくれて
I love the present, and for loving me,
こんな歌あったねって　君が教えてくれた
You told me, "There was a song like this."
というわけで、今日は誕生日ライブ、見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
So, thank you all so much for coming to see my birthday live today!
本当に楽しかったです！なの！ありがとう！
I really had a lot of fun! Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!